<?xml version="1.0"?>
    <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
    <title>Eliora Hansonbrook</title>
    <link>https://hansonbrook.com</link>
    <description>The latest posts from the blog</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2025 Eliiora Hansonbrook. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <managingEditor>eliora@hansonbrook.com</managingEditor>
<item>
<title>The Murder of Sam Nordquist</title>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 12:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>Eliora Hansonbrook</author>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Sam Nordquist was born at the turn of the millennium and <a href="https://www.republicaneagle.com/news/missing-former-red-wing-high-school-student-found-dead-in-new-york/article_018779de-eba6-11ef-93be-1f3d6992fb29.html">grew up</a> in Red Wing, Minnesota with a loving family. Like other young people, he went through typical coming-of-age milestones: he attended high school, got <a href="https://www.pghlesbian.com/2025/02/biracial-trans-man-sam-nordquist-24-missing-from-minnesota-tortured-and-killed-in-canandaigua-new-york/">dozens of tattoos</a>, and came to know himself better. But unlike most young people, in discovering himself, he discovered that, although he had been assigned female at birth, his gender identity was male.</p>
<p>Mr. Nordquist continued living in the Twin Cities area as he entered adulthood; living either in Saint Paul or Oakdale, Minnesota, depending on the source. Sometime late last year he <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/crime/have-you-seen-sam-nordquist-nysp-searching-for-missing-man-last-seen-in-canandaigua/ar-AA1z02fk">flew to New York State</a>. He would never return to Minnesota.</p>
<p>On Saturday, The New York Times <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/15/nyregion/ny-arrests-sam-nordquist-murder.html">reported</a> on his murder. Mr. Nordquist was tortured for over a month, murdered, and and then dumped in a field in upstate New York. Although police have not publicly stated a motive for the crime, it is difficult for me to imagine that Mr. Nordquist would have been tortured and murdered for anything other than his identity.</p>
<p>Even in a country where dozens of transgender people are murdered for their gender identities every year, the allegations in this case are particularly repugnant. Police allege that Mr. Nordquist “was subjected to prolonged physical and psychological abuse before being transported to Yates County, where the remains were disposed of.” To be murdered for who you are is horrific; to be tortured for over a month first is nauseating. Worse, this wasn’t some lone actor: five separate people have already been charged in his murder; more charges may be on the way.</p>
<p>The <a href="https://troopers.ny.gov/news/updatenew-york-state-police-seek-public-assistance-locating-missing-person">allegations</a> made by New York State police seem consistent with a targeted, premeditated murder. This was not a crime of passion; it was a persecution. Yet despite a month of torture, it was only after Mr. Nordquist’s family lost contact with him and asked law enforcement to conduct a wellness check, that the state became involved.</p>
<p>Mr. Nordquist’s murder should shock our nation. It is reminiscent of some of the most infamous crimes in American history; <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matthew_Shepard">Matthew Shepard’s 1998 murder</a> in Wyoming, among others. Throughout human history, people have been killed because of who they are. They are killed because they are looked down upon, dehumanized, and denigrated. It is not enough to not commit the crime; we are obligated, as members of society, to stand up to the worst impulses of our fellow human beings.</p>
<p>I firmly believe that political speech is a fundamental aspect of our democracy. I don’t believe that individuals should be punished solely for their speech indirectly influencing a crime’s commission. However, given the prevalence of anti-transgender speech in our country, it seems reasonable to draw a connection between the political rhetoric used by certain individuals and the environment in which Mr. Nordquist’s murder occurred.</p>
<p>On Thursday, the same day police executed a warrant as part of their investigation into Mr. Nordquist’s disappearance, the Trump Administration <a href="https://apnews.com/article/stonewall-transgender-trump-3add180f5cfcde156f8d809d24e830a6">removed all references</a> to transgender people from the Stonewall National Monument website.</p>
<p>We can do better. We should do better. We must do better.</p>]]></description>
<link>https://hansonbrook.com/Posts/2025-02-15-the-murder-of-sam-nordquist</link>
</item>

<item>
<title>Protest Against Protectionism</title>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 12:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>Eliora Hansonbrook</author>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In 1981, 44% of the global population <a href="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SI.POV.DDAY?end=2022&amp;locations=1W&amp;start=1981&amp;view=chart">lived in extreme poverty</a>. By 2022, that number had been reduced to 9%. Although this dramatic decrease in extreme poverty has numerous causes, empirical research strongly supports the conceit that trade liberalization has been a <a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w25927/w25927.pdf">significant driver</a> of economic growth globally. Trade liberalization, often synonymous with <a href="https://www.hoover.org/research/case-free-trade">low tariffs</a>, is at the heart of the contemporary world’s unprecedented economic prosperity.</p>
<p>By allowing states to leverage <a href="https://theconversation.com/what-is-comparative-advantage-230869">comparative advantage</a>, free trade reduces redundancy and maximizes global economic output. With more efficient economic systems, prices decrease, making more comfortable lifestyles more accessible to more people. The theory of free trade, that it is a tide that lifts all boats, has broadly been born out.</p>
<p>Yet it has become clear that there are costs to the adoption of free trade. Individuals who lose jobs as a result of free trade implementation may struggle to adapt. Between 1997 and 2020, the United States <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/reshoring-manufacturing-jobs/">lost</a> approximately 90,000 manufacturing plants and five million jobs. After the People’s Republic of China joined the World Trade Organization in 2001, manufacturing communities in the U.S. were effectively abandoned overnight; cheap goods came at the expense of their jobs. Newly unemployed, these workers <a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/02/11/g-s1-47352/why-economists-got-free-trade-with-china-so-wrong">would struggle for years to find new jobs</a>. Their anger and dissatisfaction are <a href="https://econofact.org/the-politics-of-manufacturing-decline">theorized</a> to have contributed to the election of President Trump.</p>
<p>It is of little surprise then, that, since his return to the White House, Mr. Trump has campaigned to deliberalize trade. At the heart of Mr. Trump’s envisioned economic policy is his embrace of tariffs: in his first month in office he has implemented a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/02/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-imposes-tariffs-on-imports-from-canada-mexico-and-china/">10% tariff on China</a>, threatened U.S. allies <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/progress-on-the-situation-at-our-northern-border/">Canada</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/progress-on-the-situation-at-our-southern-border/">Mexico</a> with 25% across-the-board tariffs, and is promising so-called “<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/02/president-trump-demands-fair-reciprocal-trade/">reciprocal</a>” tariffs on countries around the world.</p>
<p>Although there is understandable rage against the free trade regime, Mr. Trump’s indiscriminate measures will almost certainly raise prices, and just as certainly fail to return jobs to the United States. The New York Times reports that construction costs are <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/15/realestate/trump-tariffs-home-builders-construction.html">projected to increase</a> as a result of Trump’s tariffs; N.P.R. reports that tariffs could <a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/12/23/nx-s1-5214649/avocados-tariffs-mexico-trump-organic">increase the price of food</a> imported from Mexico.</p>
<p>If Mr. Trump’s goal is to rectify the damage done to U.S. manufacturing communities by economic liberalization, there are better options than tariffs. The federal government could sponsor job training programs for workers in communities left behind by free trade, for instance. Alternatively, the federal government could subsidize manufacturing in military-critical industries, simultaneously safeguarding both our national security and the livelihoods of Americans left behind by forces outside of their control. Mr. Trump could even continue to persue <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inflation_Reduction_Act">the path towards a renewable future</a> laid out by President Biden. And in terms of positive-sum investments in American manufacturing, this is just the tip of the iceberg.</p>
<p>By choosing to pursue a retributive regime of tariffs, Mr. Trump won’t only be punishing foreign states. In the end, it is Americans who will pay the cost of Mr. Trump’s war on free trade: in the grocery store aisle, at the car dealership, and on retail websites. Even in the unlikely event that Mr. Trump is successful at restoring American manufacturing, he will only accomplish it through massive economic shocks. Shocks, mind you, that are likely far greater than those experienced in American manufacturing communities over the past several decades.</p>
<p>Not only will there be massive shocks if Mr. Trump continues to implement his tariffs, but economists have empirically proven that tariffs suppress economic growth. Even if we get past the macroeconomic shocks of the tariffs, even if manufacturing jobs return to the U.S., we will still be dealing with reduced growth in perpetuity. The needs of the few will come before the needs of the many.</p>
<p>Running the world’s largest economy (measured by nominal G.D.P.) is a complicated job. But I think that it is an indisputable political miscalculation to privilege the economic complaint, no matter how legitimate, of a small minority of one’s political supporters at the expense of the entire country’s economic future.</p>]]></description>
<link>https://hansonbrook.com/Posts/2025-02-15-protest-against-protectionism</link>
</item>

<item>
<title>Between the River and the Ceasefire</title>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 12:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>Eliora Hansonbrook</author>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Three weeks into the six-week Israel-Hamas ceasefire agreement, the situation is growing dicy. The agreement, which once looked like a promising beginning to a long-term pause in the war, now seems like it may simply prove a temporary lull. Worse, it seems possible that, thanks to Hamas, the ceasefire may not even survive its intended six weeks.</p>
<p>After President Trump’s <a href="https://apnews.com/article/israel-trump-gaza-netanyahu-169d497ac07760ccb9724bef5982338a">recent statement</a> expressing interest in taking control of the Gaza Strip, Hamas has few good options. The organization, which has a history of prioritizing <a href="https://www.wsj.com/world/middle-east/gaza-chiefs-brutal-calculation-civilian-bloodshed-will-help-hamas-626720e7">public opinion</a> over conventional military success, is likely to prefer a conflict with Israel to mass exodus of Palestinians from the Gaza Strip and a loss of geopolitical relevance. </p>
<p>If Hamas believes President Trump is serious about taking control over the Gaza Strip, the most rational position for the organization is to continue the war. That leaves the organization with a conundrum, however: if Hamas violates the ceasefire first, it may well lead to the U.S. directly intervening in the conflict. The pressures being exerted on Hamas, then, seem destined to drive it to do exactly what it appears to be doing: manipulating Israel into violating the ceasefire.</p>
<h2>The Ceasefire</h2>
<p>As a reminder, the crux of the <a href="https://apnews.com/article/gaza-israel-palestinians-ceasefire-war-cb56a3da64e144492decfffc40c589cf">ceasefire deal</a> is a hostage exchange: for each of the thirty-three hostages Hamas will release as part of the agreement, Israel will release either thirty or fifty Palestinian prisoners, depending on the hostage being released. As part of the ceasefire agreement, Israel has withdrawn from much of the Gaza Strip, allowing Hamas to reassert control over much of the Strip.</p>
<p>The terms of the deal appear, at first blush, broadly advantageous to Hamas. Yet the cease-fire agreement also allows Israel to save face. Israel stated two major military objectives in prosecuting its war against Hamas: to recover the hostages and to dismantle the quasi-governmental terrorist organization. On the first front, Israel has broadly failed. Although the I.D.F. successfully recovered a handful of hostages, high profile failures, including the <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2023/12/15/middleeast/idf-accidentally-kills-hostages-gaza/index.html">accidental killing of escaped hostages by I.D.F. soldiers</a> have proven the difficulty of accomplishing this objective through direct military force. The safest and most effective way to recover hostages is through negotiation.</p>
<p>On the second front, however, Israel set itself an impossible task. Completely destroying Hamas was never a serious possibility, given its nature as a multi-national organization. What Israel accomplished instead – killing, by U.S. estimates, <a href="https://www.timesofisrael.com/us-said-to-believe-israel-killed-just-20-30-of-hamas-terrorists-in-gaza-fighting/">more than 10,000 enemy combatants</a>, including October 7th mastermind Yahya Sinwar – was likely as close to achieving this goal as it could come. Continuing to prosecute the war in the Gaza Strip serves little purpose other than furthering Israel’s international isolation.</p>
<p>Despite a nominally favorable ceasefire deal, Hamas seems dissatisfied with letting sleeping dogs lie. The organization has released its hostages in humiliating and <a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/israel-hamas-gaza-ceasefire-3rd-hostage-release-prisoner-exchange/">unacceptable</a> ways. Some hostages <a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c6267kyp0eko">were dressed up in military fatigues</a>, some forced to <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2025/01/30/middleeast/israel-gaza-hostage-release-chaos-intl-latam/index.html">march through an angry crowd</a>, others were <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/02/08/world/middleeast/israel-hamas-hostages-prisoners.html">forced to deliver speeches at gunpoint</a> directly before their release. These actions don’t just demean the hostages; they endanger the ceasefire agreement itself. By turning hostage releases into spectacles, Hamas is vindicating the Israeli far-right, <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/world/israel-far-right-hostage-families-cease-fire-negotiation-rcna126486">which opposed a ceasefire deal</a> in the first place. If Prime Minister Netanyahu chooses to use military force to punish Hamas, he will violate the terms of the ceasefire. If he simply allows them to continue as they are doing, his already struggling far-right coalition in the Knesset may collapse.</p>
<p>Ultimately, Hamas’ hostage releases seem calculated to exert exactly the sort of domestic political pressure on Israeli leaders that could lead to them violating the ceasefire agreement. And while Hamas was already dramatizing hostage releases, it seems likely that the organization will double down on that strategy in the wake of President Trump’s announcement.</p>
<p>Should Israel actually violate the ceasefire agreement, the results would be catastrophic for it. It is a distinct possibility that Israel violating a ceasefire agreement would result in both economic sanctions and political censure. South Africa’s case against Israel in the International Court of Justice would be strengthened, as would the International Criminal Court case against Mr. Netanyahu.</p>
<p>In traditional military terms, the results of Israel violating the ceasefire agreement could be catastrophic for Hamas, as well. But Hamas is not fighting a war with conventional military measures of success. Hamas is trying to win the war for public opinion, and, unfortunately for Israel, Hamas seems to be winning. If Israel breaches a ceasefire agreement, regardless of the domestic pressure its leaders may be experiencing, everyday international observers will likely miss that essential context. Instead, they will likely perceive Israel’s actions as yet another instance of misconduct. And then they’ll go vote for politicians who are unfriendly towards Israel.</p>
<h2>Where We Are Now</h2>
<p>It’s impossible to know for certain whether I am correct about Hamas’ aims. There is no question that Israel and Hamas hold deep animosity for, and low opinions of, one another, however. In this light, I struggle to see how Hamas could not imagine that its management of hostage releases is endangering the ceasefire. Particularly after well-documented Israeli complaints on the subject.</p>
<p>I want to believe that the ceasefire will last beyond the first six weeks. But President Trump’s declaration of interest in acquiring Gaza threatens Hamas’ territorial sovereignty and geopolitical relevance. Hamas has opposed Palestinian exodus from the Gaza Strip throughout the war. If Hamas is a rational actor, it will almost certainly prefer an endless, meaningless, brutal war to a peace without a Palestine.</p>
<p>Baiting Israel may not even be particularly difficult: the Israeli far-right would be more than happy to continue the war in Gaza. After all, there is a nearly two decade precedent for Hamas and the Israeli far-right to tacitly collaborate. The Israeli and the Palestinian far-right may hate each other, but they can agree on one thing: there should only be one state between the river and the sea.</p>]]></description>
<link>https://hansonbrook.com/Posts/2025-02-08-between-the-river-and-the-ceasefire</link>
</item>

<item>
<title>Two Weeks</title>
<pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 12:00:00 -0000</pubDate>
<author>Eliora Hansonbrook</author>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The past two weeks have been... interesting.</p>
<p>I don’t mean interesting in the sense that “oh, everything is fine, dandy, and really grabs my attention.” I mean interesting in the sense that “better pay attention ‘cause the world sure doesn’t look like it’s in a great place.”</p>
<p>Two weeks ago, President Trump returned to office. Since that day, his administration has committed to a wide variety of divisive and destructive decisions. I am of the opinion that the actions Mr. Trump has taken so far undermine our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/imposing-duties-to-address-the-flow-of-illicit-drugs-across-our-national-border/">economy</a>, our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/reinstating-service-members-discharged-under-the-militarys-covid-19-vaccination-mandate/">military</a>, our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-radical-indoctrination-in-k-12-schooling/">democratic values</a>, and the future of the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/putting-america-first-in-international-environmental-agreements/">global climate</a>.</p>
<p>While I disapprove of these actions, I am far more concerned about the ways in which the Trump Administration is systematically dehumanizing people who live in our country. Mass deportations of immigrants don’t just <a href="https://insight.kellogg.northwestern.edu/article/immigrants-to-the-u-s-create-more-jobs-than-they-take">undermine our economy</a>; they ruin people’s lives. Immigration agents carrying out arrests have allegedly arrested people, including natural born American citizens, based on the <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/latino/trump-immigration-raids-citizens-profiling-accusations-native-american-rcna189203">color of their skin</a>.</p>
<p>Immigrants are not alone in being singled out by the Trump Administration. The transgender community, to which I belong, has been repeatedly targeted in the past two weeks. Not only have we been <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/prioritizing-military-excellence-and-readiness/">banned from serving our country</a> in the armed forces, but the executive order doing so referred to us as unable to live an “honorable, truthful, and disciplined lifestyle,” and declared us “mentally and physically [un]fit for duty.”</p>
<p>Unsatisfied with simply denying transgender Americans the opportunity to serve their country, Mr. Trump’s administration has targeted the youngest members of our community. He has signed executive orders cutting off <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/protecting-children-from-chemical-and-surgical-mutilation/">access to healthcare</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/ending-radical-indoctrination-in-k-12-schooling/">cracking down</a> on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gender_transition#Social,_psychological,_and_aesthetic_aspects">social transition</a> in schools, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/01/initial-rescissions-of-harmful-executive-orders-and-actions/">repealed</a> legal protections for our community.</p>
<p>Now, I realize you, dear reader, might have questions about the transgender community. That’s perfectly understandable. But the actions currently being taken by the Trump Administration don’t seem particularly interested in asking questions. Instead, they seem calculated to erase transgender people from public life, as <a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/politics/politics-news/cpac-speaker-transgender-people-eradicated-1234690924/">promised by Michael Knowles</a> two years ago at CPAC.</p>
<p>These attacks on immigrants and the transgender community compose a vividly disturbing picture: a presidential administration which sees ordinary Americans as less than human. I know the effects of the actions taken by this administration have affected me personally. Over the past two weeks I’ve struggled to go through the motions of everyday life. For the last few days I’ve felt as though I was in a dark pit with no way out. Everything felt gray, bland, and dark. Maybe you’ve felt this way, too.</p>
<p>After three particularly difficult days, I decided continuing that way was untenable. I needed to channel my angst into something substantial. That something substantial is this blog. Unlike traditional blogs, I’m creating this blog for myself. It’s still accessible to the public, of course, but my primary audience is my own well being. Although I anticipate writing primarily about politics, it’s likely I’ll also touch on many other topics which interest me. Expect pieces on linguistics, economics, and computer science. I might also write about my personal life and publish both literary and visual art I create.</p>
<p>You’ll probably disagree with me sometimes. That’s okay. People <em>should</em> disagree with one another. But also, this website is for me. You’re welcome to come and take a look to see what I’m up to, and I look forward to your thoughtful comments and criticisms. I fervently believe that a core component of a healthy democracy is a healthy political discourse, and I welcome your feedback. Ultimately, however, I’ll publish what I want to publish.</p>
<p>At the college I attend, students spray paint a rock in the center of campus with messages. The current message? “America is bleeding.” If our beautiful country is bleeding, I think the best way to stifle the bleeding is by sharing.</p>]]></description>
<link>https://hansonbrook.com/Posts/2025-02-02-two-weeks</link>
</item>

        </channel>
    </rss>
    